# David Pehshvelashvili

## FRONT-FND DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

Experienced in creating applications with React, Redux, REST, ES6+, Typescript, HTML, CSS. I'm always looking forward to improve my expertise. Mainly interested in front-end technologies, however I've started getting familiar with back-end (Node.js) lately and got drawn into it. So I strive to expand my competence and become a Full-Stack Developer eventually.

#### RECENT SKILLS

#### TECHNICAL:

- React, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Thunk, Saga
- · HTTPS, RestAPI, Axios
- Javascript (ES6+), Typescript
- HTML, CSS, SASS, UI/UX
- · TDD, Jest, Storybook, Git
- · Material UI, Ant Design
- · Webpack, Babel
- · Agile methodology

#### LANGUAGES:

- Russian Native Speaker
- · English Proficient

#### **EDUCATION**

#### 2020

IT - Incubator

Front-end development / React, Redux, Typescript, REST, Git, Team development

#### 2014 - 2017

Financial University under the Government of the Russian Federation / Governmental Financial management / Moscow, Russia 2011 - 2014

Business College of Economics / Banking Industry. / Moscow, Russia



Russia, Moscow

+7 (915) 293-91-14

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER

#### FREELANCE / START-UP | November 2020 - Present

- Project architectural solutions (layering UI, BLL, DAL)
- Implementation of new features such as:
  - RESTful (Registration / loginization / pagination etc.)
  - Proper BLL state management with Redux, Thunk etc.
  - TDD with Jest, Storybook, Postman
  - Performance enhancement (memo, useCallback, lazy, Suspense etc.)
  - Migration to Typescript

#### **FINANCIAL EXPERT**

# STATE CLINICAL RESEARCH CENTRE FOR CHILDREN | May 2015 - Jun 2020

- Management, planning and optimization of financial and business operations
- State purchases of supplies, communication with insurance companies
- · Report preparation for higher-level State Agencies

#### PERSONAL FITNESS TRAINER

#### SELF-EMPLOYED | Feb 2019 - Apr 2020

- · Composition of individual fitness and nutrition programs
- · Individual consultations

#### **ENGLISH TUTOR**

### SELF-EMPLOYED | May 2017 - Nov 2018

- Development of English learning road maps for different purposes (Exams, Business, Artistic etc.)
- Preparing students for State Exams